We're riding towards Absolution.
You know how far west we are?
Maybe he's a dummy.
Is there a reason
you're not answering my question?
Look here, Pa.
He's got iron on his wrist.
He's been shot.
Could be he done
broke out of the hoosegow.
Might be worth bounty money.
Might could be.
It's not your lucky day, stranger.
Turn around and start walking.
I said turn around and start walking!
Get out.
Hello?
Palms to heaven, friend.
Easy now.
All right. Turn around, nice and slow.
I've been shot.
Only two kinds of men get shot,
criminals and victims.
Which one are you?
I don't know.
You got a name, friend?
I don't know that either.
Just what do you know?
English.
Well, that is a right odd-looking
wound there.
Looks almost cauterized.
All right, this might sting a bit.
Is this a mining town?
Yeah. Well, that was the notion.
People moved on, though. No gold.
All right now, try and hold still.
There we go.
This is no gunshot.
Where'd you get this, son?
I don't know.
I can't rightly absolve you of your sins
if you don't recall 'em, can I?
That being said,
I've seen good men do bad things
and bad men do good things.
Whether you're gonna
end up in heaven or hell,
it's not God's plan, it's your own.
You just got to remember what it was.
All right, put me a finger right here.
Come on.
There you go.
There.
Thank you.
Not bad for a country preacher.
It's that damn fool Dolarhyde kid.
Hey! What are you doing?
What are you doing, Percy?
There's people up there!
There's no one up there. It's fine.
It's not fine.
It's bad enough he drinks for free.
Now he's got to shoot up the place?
Wait, what was that, Doc?
Nothing. He didn't say anything.
Everything's okay.
Please go back inside.
Shut up.
I want to hear what you said.
"It's bad enough" what?
You ungrateful for our business?
'Cause if it wasn't for my pa's cattle,
there'd be no money
going through this town!
There'd be no meat on your tables!
And your doors would be closed!
I don't mean no disrespect
to your father, Percy. You know that.
Of course not.
But you ask me to pay.
Come here, let's settle up.
Come here.
Hey.
Hey, kid, I don't want any trouble.
I'm just trying to...
Better pick up your glasses, Doc,
before someone steps on them.
Stop!
I'll pay the goddamn bill!
All right, son! We're just trying
to make a living now. Come on.
You know what, preacher?
You just gave me an idea.
I know it ain't Sunday, folks,
but what say we take up
a collection for the poor man?
Now, who's got money?
In the hat.
Let's go.
Much obliged.
Now, I'm sorry Doc's bad fortune
has to be taken out on you good people.
In the hat.
That's mighty Christian of you.
Hey.
You, too.
You want to be careful where you point
that thing before you get hurt.
Listen...
I'm gonna give you
the benefit of the doubt, because
maybe you don't know who I am.
- Come on.
- Get off of me!
Hey, you!
I'm warning you.
Are you all right?
Where the hell did he come from?
What the hell is going on here?
It was an accident.
He came out of nowhere.
And he dry-gulched me.
He tried to make me look like a fool.
It wasn't my fault, Sheriff.
Damn it, Percy. You crossed the line
this time. I gotta lock you up.
Taggart.
You know that's not a good idea.
Well, I'm afraid I got no choice, Nat.
Nat?
Nat, you son of a bitch,
where you going?
Don't worry. I'll tell your father
about what happened today.
You burned the coffee again, Mickey.
Well. Tell you what, Ed.
Next time, you can make the coffee.
- Okay.
- All right.
Why don't you take it easy
on that Taos Lightnin', Murphy?
Mr. Dolarhyde
don't like drinking on the job.
don't like drinking on the job?
I don't give a rat's ass what the high
and mighty Colonel Dolarhyde don't like!
I don't care how many Indians
he put under neither.
You sure do flap your gums a lot
when the boss ain't around.
I'd say it to his face if he was here!
Colonel Dolarhyde.
I'm gonna tell you something, boys.
Money makes you soft.
Where the hell's that coach?
Coach? What coach?
You shot a deputy, Percy.
Federal Marshal's
bringing you to Santa Fe.
Federal Marshal?
Sheriff, have you lost your mind?
My pa is on his way down here.
You better let me out of here
before things get out of hand.
Sheriff, it was an accident!
It's not like I'm Jesse James!
Son of a bitch.
Could you put that on Percy's tab?
Fifty cents.
Just kidding with you, there, Doc.
I got no respect in this town.
That's not true, okay?
You want to leave?
No. This is your dream.
I'd follow you anywhere.
I thought it was our dream.
God damn it!
Hey, Charlie,
why don't you play something festive?
It's like a funeral in here!
Hey, you don't have
to prove anything, okay?
Okay? I love you.
I'm not a child.
Whiskey.
On the house, for what you did.
I'm just here to drink.
- Do I know you?
- No.
My name's Ella.
Where'd you get your bracelet?
There something you know about me,
lady?
You don't remember anything, do you?
What do you want?
I know you're looking for something.
So am I.
Well, good luck to you.
Move away.
Jake Lonergan.
You mind following me
over to the office,
so we can have us a little chat?
I think you've got the wrong man.
Well, I'm gonna need you
to come with us all the same.
Wouldn't do that if I was you.
No!
I don't want any trouble.
Rise and shine.
You're in trouble now.
You're gonna burn.
My pa is coming for me.
He learned how to kill a man
good and slow in the war.
I am going to watch you suffer
for a long,
long,
long time.
You thought
that cheap shot in the pecker hurt?
Please! I didn't kill your cattle.
Colonel Dolarhyde.
You got to believe me!
You only been riding for my brand
for what, two weeks?
You don't maybe know
who you're dealing with, Roy.
Nobody calls me "Colonel."
Them that did are mostly dead.
Please.
So you, Ed and Little Mickey is picking
up strays. How many did you get?
Got 24 of 'em, boss.
You been drinking, ain't you?
I can smell it on you.
I haven't been drinking none.
It's them other two's that drinked.
What kind of a man goes around
blowing up other people's cows
then tells a bullshit story like this?
You couldn't do no better?
You got to believe me.
There was white lights!
There was bright lights!
So there was this big light,
and you fell in the river
and when you come back,
two of my best hands
has just disappeared.
There weren't no storm.
There weren't no lightning this evening.
You don't respect me, do you, Roy?
Boss!
Where's Percy?
Taggart locked him up, boss.
Why? What'd he do now?
Shot a deputy.
God damn it!
What the hell
does Taggart think he's doing?
He wouldn't even have a job if I...
Now I got to go in there
and reason with him!
'Cause you failed to look after my boy!
Thank you. Thank you.
All right. Everybody, saddle up.
Boss, we ought to get more hands.
Why?
You're not gonna believe this,
but I think Jake Lonergan's in town.
I'm turning you over
to the Federal Marshal.
You're gonna tell me
what I am charged with?
Arson. Assault.
Mayhem. Hijacking.
It says you robbed the stage last month
with Pat Dolan and Bull McCade.
Which makes you
accessory to every law they broke, too.
That it?
Murder.
Prostitute out of Cottonwood Grove,
next county over.
Name of Alice Wills.
You saying I killed this woman?
You tell me.
Damn.
Give me your wrist.
Taggart, what are you doing?
Sheriff.
Sheriff, this is going too far.
I was just fooling around.
Look, I didn't mean to hurt anybody.
Go away.
Listen, I'm sorry, but I had no choice.
I couldn't let you leave.
Well, I'm leaving now.
I need you.
You got something to say, say it.
I need to know where you came from.
So do I.
Ma'am.
You two lovebirds have a nice trip now.
Taggart! Taggart, let me out of here!
Sheriff!
What are you doing?
You get back home. Go to bed.
Please don't go.
I have to, Emmett. It's my job.
I don't like it here.
Your pa's getting things in order.
When he does he'll send for you.
It's been a year.
Don't worry, he will.
And your mom's buried here.
You know I can't leave my little girl.
- Taggart?
- Yeah, I see them.
Emmett, you go inside. Now.
I want my boy, John.
Pa?
Pa!
I knew you'd come for me, Pa.
Shut up! I'll deal with you later.
Yeah, that's Lonergan, boss.
That's the son of a bitch
stole my gold off the bullion coach.
I want that man.
You're gonna have to take it up
with the judge in Santa Fe.
I ain't going to Santa Fe.
You give him to me now
or I'm gonna take him.
What about me, Pa?
I said, shut up, boy!
What the hell is that?
What the hell?
Hey!
- They're coming back!
- They're coming around again.
They're coming back! Dismount!
- Get out of the way!
- Maria!
Oh, God!
Don't move! Don't move!
Stay there! Stay right there!
Don't move! I'm coming!
Give me your hand.
- Give me your hand.
- What the hell for?
I can get us free.
Just give me your hand.
Hold still.
Emmett!
Grandpa!
Emmett, it's all right. I got you, son.
- Give me your hand.
- No!
Come on, kid. Give me your hand!
What is that?
Come on, get up, boss.
Come on, we got to get out of here.
Where's Percy?
Come on out of there!
- I can't, Pa.
- You can't? Coward!
He broke my fingers!
Pa!
Let's go! We got to go!
This way!
- What is that thing?
- Why are you asking me?
Because you shot it!
With that thing.
Where'd you get that thing?
I don't know.
What do you mean, you don't know?
What the hell is that?
They took my wife.
Hey.
Is anyone in there?
No.
Is my wife in there?
No!
Is it dead?
- Is it demons?
- Demons?
I can't rightly say.
Sure does fit the description, but...
Demons? What are you talking about?
You talking about Bible stuff? Demons?
- I'm not talking about anything.
- What the hell are you talking about?
You got to calm down, Doc.
- Calm down?
- You're scaring the boy.
You're telling me a bunch of demons
took my wife.
- I didn't say any such thing.
- Took our people!
- Get a hold of yourself.
- You're telling me to calm down!
Boss!
It went this way.
I don't know what it is, but it's bleeding.
That's the same direction
those machines went with our kin.
We ain't gonna be able to track it
in the dark.
Round up the horses,
get some supplies!
We'll set off at first light!
You.
You're going with us.
I need that weapon. It's the only thing
that counts. And I figure you owe me.
I don't see it that way.
What do you want?
You come clean right now, or I'll kill you.
They took my people, too.
I've been looking for them a long time.
I know you can help me find them.
You stay away from me.
I can help you!
It's heading north.
Its tracks are still fresh.
If it's all the same,
I'd like to ride along, too.
Yes, ma'am.
Got a kid and a dog, why not a woman?
You're back.
What's that?
You have to take it back.
Like hell I will.
That's blood money.
- Well, I goddamned earned it.
- By robbing and killing.
That's gonna get us what we need!
- Jake!
- Stay there!
Jake!
Well, well, well.
Look who's back.
I see you, but I don't see my gold.
Let's say we find those people first,
and then you can take your best shot
at collecting.
Maybe that reward on your head
would be a more attractive proposition.
Or I could just shoot you in the chest
and cut that thing off your arm.
You know, Doc,
I don't even know why we're doing this.
You know they're all dead.
Well, I think if they wanted to kill them,
I think they would have.
Only if the boss is right
and they was roping them.
Bet it's to eat them.
If it was me, I'd start with your wife.
You gonna be like this the whole trip?
'Cause if you are,
we ain't gonna have
too many long conversations, are we?
Why don't you sing a song
or something?
Cook some beans.
Do something useful.
Take some friendly advice?
Get yourself a gun
and learn how to use it.
The tracks are washed away.
I don't know much about boats,
but I'd say that one's upside-down.
We're 500 miles from any river
big enough to hold it.
Well, let's get inside, get out of the rain!
I'm not going anywhere near that thing.
Suit yourself. Sleep in the rain.
You fixin' to say something?
Maybe...
Maybe we should have
called in the Army?
I ain't gonna turn this over
to no West Pointers
who got to get on the telegraph to ask
Washington which hand to wipe with.
I waited around at Antietam
for 'em to tell me what to do.
And lost 328 men
over a cornfield.
I remember those stories.
I don't recollect telling you any stories.
I'd listen when you'd tell them to Percy.
You get this through
your thick Indian skull.
Them stories weren't for you.
They were for my son.
Get out of here.
Go look after the horses. Do your job.
You've been looking at this knife.
You like this knife?
You look after that.
Don't lose it.
Don't yank on it, it's not your pecker.
Now, here.
You're holding onto this thing
like you're hanging from it.
What the hell am I doing?
It's my fault she got took.
I never should have
taken her to that town.
No, no, no. Not your fault.
You'll get her back.
You're setting things right.
Just got to have faith. That's all.
Faith. Yeah.
God's been real swell to me.
I don't mean no disrespect, preacher,
but either he ain't up there,
or he don't like me very much.
Surely you don't expect the Lord
to do everything for you, do you, Doc?
You got to earn his presence.
Then you got to recognize it,
and then you have to act on it.
Now, keep your eye on the target.
And shoot.
That's better. Better.
Come on. Let's reload.
You been there long?
Yes.
There something you need?
Who is she?
She's the only one who knows who I am.
No, you know who you are.
- You just have to remember.
- Well, I can't.
Yes, you can.
Does it hurt?
It's fine.
It's here.
Easy, hey! Easy!
What's wrong, boy?
Hello?
Get away from that boy!
No!
- The boy. The boy.
- He's fine. He's fine.
It's okay. It's okay.
You go get our people back.
God don't care who you were, son.
Only who you are.
Dog?
Come on, boy!
Where are you?
Tracks are good. It's headed north.
Where's the men?
They run off. Goddamn cowards.
I can't find the dog.
We ain't waiting for him.
He's run off or dead. Let's go.
Hey. Hey. Wait.
Aren't we gonna
say some words over him?
Only one who knows what to say
is in the ground.
Ain't it enough we took the time
to put him there?
No. No, it's not enough.
You go ahead.
Lord...
If there is such a thing as a soul
this man had a good one.
Please protect it.
Made me feel better.
World was a better place
for having him.
Dust to dust, amen. How was that?
Good words.
What are you all choked up about?
I'm worried about my grandpa.
Look. When I was only just
a little bit older than you are now
all this was Mexico.
Word come that the Apaches was riding
towards a settlement called Arivaca.
My father wanted me to be a man,
so he made me ride out with
the garrison, banging on a drum.
Boy, was I scared.
Well, we got there, it was too late.
They were all dead,
the place was all burnt down.
This one settler fella
came crawling out of a burning cabin.
He was bad.
He knew he was gonna die.
Burnt bad.
He rolled over,
looked up into my eyes,
and he said, "Kill me."
What did you do?
I took this knife off his belt
and I slit his throat.
Take it.
Be a man.
That's a little rough, isn't it?
He means well.
I got him.
The tracks are closer together.
He's slowing down,
headed to that canyon.
Put your hands up in the air!
That means you, too, pretty lady.
This is what they call a hold-up.
Welcome, everybody. Welcome.
Boss?
Boss, is that you?
Lonergan?
What in the hell are you doing here?
Who are your amigos?
Is this your new gang, Jake?
I never thought I'd see you again, Jake.
You were always my favorite.
Shut up.
Damn it.
Jake? Did you break my tooth?
Would you shut up? I'm thinking.
How many boys we got left?
About the same.
Which is?
Thirty?
That's right. Thirty.
Good.
- That's good.
- Yeah.
You're gonna bring me to the camp.
It's time to set things straight.
We're gonna go to the camp!
How's the haul?
Vulture Mine gold. Looking pretty rich.
- How much dynamite we get?
- We got 50 sticks or so.
Dolan!
About time you got back.
What the hell happened to you?
He did.
Well, shit.
You got some balls
riding back in here
like nothing ever happened.
Boys! Grab your guns. We're riding out.
Boys aren't going anywhere with you,
Jake.
We're fixing to rob us a coach.
And that's exactly what we're gonna do.
Are you her?
Am I who?
The whore that Jake quit this gang for.
You watch your mouth.
Or what?
I run this outfit now.
Put your guns on the whore!
If he so much as twitches,
blow her brains out of her ear.
He said the whore.
You call her a whore again,
it'll be the last word you ever say.
You ain't in no position
to make threats, boyo.
Hunt, take his gun.
Take his gun!
Sorry, Jake.
Where's our gold, Jake?
I don't remember.
Well, I do remember
you telling us you was leaving us
high and dry because of some woman.
I guess you just left out the part about
taking all of our gold from that last job?
So I'm gonna ask you one last time.
Where is it, Jake?
Demons.
What's that?
Demons took your gold.
When you get to hell
you can ask for it back.
Kill the whore.
I told you not to call her that.
Everybody!
Drop 'em!
I said drop 'em!
Not fun, is it?
You know, that wasn't very nice.
On your horses!
Go!
Jake, Jake, Jake. Don't forget your gun.
You'll always be my favorite.
- Mount up!
- Ride!
- They're here!
- Move out!
Come on!
Okay. I got you!
I got you!
Can you swim?
Oh, God.
Turn your head!
You all right?
Let's get in.
We were flying.
Yeah!
I don't want to do that again.
No.
Hey.
Hey, you stay with me.
Keep talking.
You remember now, don't you?
What?
The woman.
Did you love her?
You can tell me.
I can't remember.
I must've.
All I know is I owe it to her
to find her.
Watch out. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I got you.
It's not far now.
You and me,
we're gonna be just fine.
Is that...
Is that them?
Boss?
- I got her.
- Give her to me, Nat. Bring her here.
- Here. Drink.
- No. Give it to her. Give it to her.
Doc?
How is she?
She's gone, pal.
No. No, she's not gone.
She's not. She's not gone!
Jake.
She's gone.
- Doc!
- Don't touch him!
Doc!
This is Black Knife.
The last of his people.
There's no reasoning with them.
We're all gonna die anyway.
This is what's left of the Chiricahuas.
Good riddance to 'em!
He's saying the white people,
they brought all this evil to his people.
We brought evil? Evil was here!
You're the evil one!
He's saying we brought the monsters.
We didn't bring the monsters.
Tell him they took our people, too!
Tell him they took my wife!
Shut up!
There's no reasoning with them!
Tell him what I said, Nat!
Kill us now!
I'm sorry, but I couldn't tell you.
Are you one of them?
No. I'm from a different place.
I took this form
so I could walk among you.
You should have told me.
I didn't know if I could heal this body,
if I would wake up.
He wants to know where you're from.
What'd she say?
She says she came from a place
above the stars.
What does that mean? Another world?
What do you mean?
What does that mean? What?
He says you shouldn't talk.
What do you mean I shouldn't talk?
I got questions...
You're a guest of the chief.
Now I'm a guest? I thought
I was a prisoner! What the hell am I?
Enough! All right. You're both big men!
Great warriors!
Can we just listen to the woman
tell her story?
Or whatever she is?
What are they doing here?
They want gold.
Well, that's just ridiculous.
What are they gonna do,
buy something?
It's as rare to them as it is to you.
What about my grandpa?
What about my wife? What about
the other people? Are they still alive?
If they are, they won't be for long.
They're studying your weaknesses.
These are just scouts.
If we let them leave, they'll come back
with more and there will be no survivors.
That's what they did to my people.
I came here to make sure
it would not happen again,
but we have to work together.
He says his people will join her.
What do you mean, join her?
What's she going to do?
Where you going to go?
We can find them.
He knows where they are.
No, I don't.
I can't remember anything.
I couldn't even remember my own name.
He says they will take care of that.
I brought the gold.
Into the house.
That's why she died.
It's not your fault.
I know where they are.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
How did they build something like that?
They arrived in it. It's their vessel.
That's only the top.
The rest is underground.
It's how they mine for gold.
So there is gold here.
Can they see out of there?
They don't see well in daylight.
They stay underground in caverns
where it's dark.
We'll never even get close.
Those flying machines
will just pick us off
before we get anywhere near it.
There is another way in.
Down there.
The way I came out.
We got to get those creatures
out of there
and out in the open,
where we can get at them.
So you can get in with that arm gun,
get our people out.
We have one advantage,
they underestimate you.
You're like insects to them.
They're not planning on defending
themselves, so they'll be vulnerable.
- We haven't got enough men.
- This ain't gonna work.
He says he wants to use your spyglass.
The Apaches are mountain warriors.
He says it's better to fight
from high ground.
Tell him he's a fool.
There is no high ground
while they got those flying machines.
Jake's leaving!
That's just dandy.
Son of a bitch.
Quit stalling.
How much gold we had left?
Barely enough.
But I'm gonna need my share right now
so I can get as far away from here
as I possibly can.
- Red?
- I got him, Bull.
Hey, there.
I had one hell of a job finding you boys.
You planning a trip?
We're going as far away as we can go.
You remember la playa
in Puerto Vallarta?
They got good fishing.
Good tequila.
You want to come with us?
Don't make no difference.
It's not far enough.
What in the hell
were those things, Jake?
It doesn't matter.
They're gonna find us
and they're gonna wipe us out.
What in the hell are you saying?
What I'm saying is you got a choice.
You can drink your last few hours away
on a beach,
which by the way, is not a bad idea
or you can follow me one last time.
We got to make the best use
of our resources.
We got to have a strict...
Listen to me, damn it!
He doesn't understand tactics.
You got to explain to him.
Look, we can't just run around hollering
and throwing spears and
shooting arrows at the damn thing.
We got to draw them out of there
onto open ground
where we can surround them,
attack them on all sides.
Flank them. Explain to him.
He said he's not going to let you
lead his people.
What's he saying?
He's saying they need to
open their hearts
and see in you what he has seen.
That his parents
died in the Mexican War
and you took him in
when he was only a boy.
That you gave him purpose.
Taught him how to take care of himself
even though you were not blood.
That you despise battle
but would never run from it.
That you're a fierce warrior
worthy of any fight.
He says if you're such a great warrior,
why do you only have a man and a boy
to follow you into battle?
Dog! Dog!
Boy!
How are you?
Hot damn.
Ready to get your son back?
Give me that. Okay.
Matches.
I don't have any more matches.
We're gonna have to go down.
I don't know what we're going to do.
Go. Go!
I think we destroyed it.
Demons are coming out.
Take this. Go up where I showed you.
- You see our people, wave your arms.
- Yes, sir.
Move out!
Good job.
If our people are in there,
I'll get them out.
Godspeed.
Let's get them!
This is how they get the gold out.
They're not going down!
They will!
Keep at it till we get our people out!
Doc!
Doc, get down here!
Jesus.
Doc!
Did we get one?
Yeah, we got one.
I always dreamed of riding into battle
with you.
I always dreamed
of having a son like you.
Go.
Get Percy.
Get your son.
Don't look into the light.
- I told you not to look into the light.
- Yeah, right.
How long are they gonna be like this?
Each one's different.
Hold them off.
You'd better hurry.
There's more of them coming!
Go!
Everybody's out.
Right.
Hey! Where are you going?
It's this way!
Go. Go!
What the hell are you doing?
We have to get out of here!
No!
I came here to destroy that thing.
How?
With the bracelet. Take it off.
Wait, I can't take it off.
Yes, you can. You can control it.
- How?
- Same way you shoot it. With your mind.
You have to stop thinking.
This isn't working.
It fell off.
If I can get it to its core,
I can stop them.
Let's go.
Take this.
Throw it!
- Good-bye, Jake.
- What?
Wait! Ella!
No!
I see them! I see them!
They got out.
They're coming out the other side!
You see Percy?
Yeah, I see him!
What about Jake and Ella?
No. They're not there.
You all right, old man?
- Where's the girl?
- She's still inside.
Go!
Grandpa!
It's me.
Emmett.
You're all grown up.
Percy.
Don't you remember me, boy?
I'm sorry. I don't remember much.
I'm your father.
Pa.
Do you remember me?
I thought you were dead.
All this gold's
gonna make things different.
We're gonna have
a railroad in here soon.
That'll change the cattle business.
Run these ledgers
back to the bank for me, will you?
Tell them I need some new checks.
Okay.
I want the new ones to read
"Dolarhyde and Son."
- That sound good to you?
- Yes. Yes, sir.
- John.
- Woodrow.
It appears our town
is about to get a whole lot bigger.
You weren't gonna leave
without saying good-bye, were you?
I'm a wanted man.
I could have sworn I saw
Jake Lonergan die in those caves,
didn't you, Sheriff?
Damn shame.
I was looking forward
to hanging him myself.
I could use a good man around here.
Yes, you could.
Jake.
She's in a better place.
I'll see you around, Colonel.
Repair and Synchronization by
Easy Subtitles Synchronizer 1.0.0.0